# Resume - Extended

# J. Caleb Wherry

Software Architect

## CONTACT

- **(**931) 338.1071
- ☑ caleb@calebwherry.com
- in linkedin.com/in/calebwherry
- ## calebwherry.com
- Atlanta, Georgia

#### SKILLS

- Software Architecture
- Mathematical Analysis
- Scientific Computing
- High-performance Computing

### EXPERTISE

- Modern C++: 11-20
- C# (.NET Core)
- Python
- GPGPU

#### EDUCATION

#### MASTER OF SCIENCE

Computer Science
Georgia Tech
2014 – TBD (On Hiatus)

#### **BACHELOR OF SCIENCE**

Computer Science
Austin Peay State University
2006 – 2011

# PROFILE

A versatile Software Architect with over 10 years of experience productizing research-driven technologies. Expert in rapidly prototyping machine learning & mathematical algorithms from first principals into production-hardened systems that scale horizontally and vertically. Technical leader and innovator that pushes the boundaries of technologies and research capabilities for core product development.

### EXPERIENCE

#### Principal Software Engineer

Nexidia, Inc | NICE / Atlanta, GA / Mar 2015 - Present

Technical lead for Research architecture and infrastructure. Rapid prototyping of C++, C# (.NET Core), & Python applications to provide efficient and robust solutions to kick-start productization of core research technologies.

- Architect for rapidly prototyped Redaction product leading to multi-millions in revenue.
- Architect for greenfield, cross-platform, containerized, gRPC-based product to modernize core research technologies for the entire tech stack.
- Productize machine learning models and inference engines using Tensorflow and ONNX in C++ and Python.
- Full SDLC support for cross-platform C++ SDK for speech research.
- Complete rewrite of build system in CMake to unify build process across Linux,
   Windows, and OSX leading to drastically reduced build and test times.
- Complete rewrite of all GPU features for better handling of errors and memory.
- Develop multiple CI driven core infrastructures for in-house model training, model building, and research tasks.
- Develop multi-threaded algorithms and infrastructure to maximize vertical scaling for production and research.
- Develop multi-node algorithms and infrastructure using REST and gRPC to maximize horizontal scaling for production and research for OnPrem and cloud environments (AWS).
- Develop new and innovative features and products for POCs and new customers.



# EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

#### Co-Founder & Chief Engineer

Korovasoft / Distributed / Jan 2008 - Present

Providing efficient and robust software solutions to the scientific community.

- Researching computational & topological optimizations in genetic algorithms.
- Studying reproduction patterns in genetic algorithms.
- Using Rust as a means to provide more robust and fault-tolerant solutions.

#### Research Scientist

Georgia Tech Research Institute / Atlanta, GA / Jun 2014 - Mar 2015

Software Architect for FPGA analysis tools. Applied mathematics research in multiple areas: circuits, graph theory, pattern matching, and computationally hard combinatorial problems.

- Developed C++ and Python tools to analyze FPGA netlists for emergent functionality using fuzzy pattern matching techniques and large-scale graph analytics.
- Complete rewrite of build system in CMake to reduce build and test times.
- Developed CI driven test system to run thousands of FPGA test suites to streamline analysis process.

#### Application Analyst & Developer

Virginia Polytechnic Institute & State University / Blacksburg, VA / Aug 2012 - May 2014

Designed, developed, and maintained document/image storage systems and workflow software.

- Complete automation of Graduate School, University Invoicing, University HR, and Student Advising work process resulting in completely paperless workflows.
- Expert in PL/SQL stored procedures for retrieval of all student information for document and workflow systems.
- Developed Java desktop application to automate scanning of documents using QR codes into the document management system.
- Created all training material and trained 100+ VaTech faculty on how to use new workflows.

## Research Engineer

Luna Innovations / Roanoke, VA / May 2011 - Aug 2012

Developed FPGA analysis tools using graph-theoretic methods.

- Developed C++ and Python tools to analyze FPGA netlists for emergent functionality using pattern matching techniques and graph-theoretic methods.
- Developed Python QA automation framework to test all tools against general FPGA designs.
- Complete rewrite of test system to use CDash and CTest with new Python QA automation framework developed.
- DARPA Trusted Integrated Circuits (TRUST) DARPA-BAA-07-24
- DARPA Integrity and Reliability of Integrated Circuits (IRIS) DARPA-BAA-10-33



#### EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

### Teaching Assistant

Austin Peay State University / Clarksville, TN / Fall 2009 - Spring 2011

Taught companion classes to main courses to help students understand material at a deeper level. Filled in for professors when absent. Courses:

- MATH 1730: Precalculus
- MATH 1910: Calculus I
- MATH 1920: Calculus II

#### Visiting Research Scholar

Institute for Quantum Computing / Waterloo, ON, CA / Summer 2010

Researched genetic algorithm optimizations for pulse sequences in control theory for superconducting and NMR qubit implementations.

- Developed C++ tools to run genetic algorithm simulations using quantum operators for fitness functions and evolution.
- GRAPE & genetic algorithm hybrid methods researched.
- Studied quantum speedups of inverse problems in general relativity and differential geometry.

# Undergraduate Researcher

Austin Peay State University / Clarksville, TN / Fall 2009

Explored mathematics involved in the construction of Julia & Mandelbrot sets.

- Analyzed the above sets in the complex and quaternion algebras geometrically.
- Developed MATLAB algorithms and parallelized using MPI on university cluster to produce high-resolution images and high-definition animations of higher dimensional sets.
- Conference presentation: "Four Dimensional Julia Sets" 119<sup>th</sup> Tennessee Academy of Science Conference (Oct 2009).
   Knoxville, TN. Won best undergraduate mathematics presentation.

#### Research Assistant

NASA JPL | CalTech / Pasadena, CA / Spring 2009, Summer 2009

Developed astrophysical software to analyze proper motion of pre-planetary nebulae.

- Developed full astrophysical software suit in IDL: PROMOS: (PROper MOtion Software).
- Image analysis C++ algorithms developed for Hubble Space Telescope images to calculate nebular proper motions.
- Streamlined astrophysical research processes with agile & modular software engineering methodologies.
- Conference presentation: "PRO-MOTIONS: PROper MOTION Software" 214<sup>th</sup> American Astronomical Society National Conference (Jun 2009). Pasadena, CA.



### EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

#### Research Assistant

NASA Langley Research Center / Hampton, VA / Fall 2008

Developed software suit for evolution of polar stratospheric clouds (PSCs) research.

- Developed trajectory and microphysical mathematical models in FORTRAN to calculate the formation and flow of currently observed PSCs.
- Developed full atmospheric science software suit in IDL to streamline LaRC scientists' cloud research processes.

#### Research Assistant

Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory (DOE) / Livermore, CA / Summer 2008

Statistically analyzed anomalous log behavior with Perl.

• Developed web-based log intrusion detection system (LIDS) written in Perl that monitored all DNS, HTTP, UDP, TCP, ICMP, CONN, and FTP logs.

## Software Development Intern

OEM Tube Assemblies / Clarksville, TN / Spring 2008

Streamlined worker interaction with machinery through FactoryPMI

- Developed hazard avoidance tools in Jython to keep employees safe in their work environment.
- Migrated MSSQL databases to MYSQL databases.

#### Network Administrator

Visitation Hospital / Petite Rivière de Nippes, Haiti / Aug 2007 - Aug 2008

Designed server system for Visitation Hospital, a free health care clinic in Haiti.

- Pro bono work to create server layout and remotely admin the network.
- Developed plugins for OpenMRS, an open source electronic medical records system written in Java.
- Troubleshot networking and software issues and management users and workflows.
- Oversaw transition of server management to local nurses and staff on site in Haiti after first year of operation.

# EDUCATION

# Georgia Institute of Technology

Master of Science, Computer Science / Atlanta, GA / Jan 2014 - Present (on hiatus)

- Concentrations: High Performance Computing and Machine Learning
- Notable courses:
  - o CS 5510: Multiprocessor Programming (transfer from VaTech)
  - o CS 7637: Knowledge-based Artificial Intelligence Cognitive Systems
  - o PHYS 5794: Computational Physics (transfer from VaTech)



# EDUCATION CONTINUED

### Austin Peay State University

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science / Clarksville, TN / Sept 2006 - May 2011

- Minors: Mathematics and Physics
- Senior Thesis: A Complexity Analysis of Shor's Quantum Factoring Algorithm
- Notable courses:
  - o CS 4230: Programming Languages
  - o MATH 4710: Real Analysis
  - o PHYS 3800: Quantum Mechanics
- Notable awards:
  - o 2011: International Mathematical Modeling Contest Honorable Mention
  - o 2006-2008: Don Waller Computer Science Scholarship
- Summer schools:
  - o 2009: Quantum Information Science For Undergraduates (QuISU), MIT
  - o 2009: Mathematical Biology & Numerical Analysis Workshop, University of Georgia
  - o 2010: Undergraduate School on Experimental Quantum Information Processing (USEQIP), IQC
  - o 2011: Modern Computational Science, *University of Oldenburg*